[Music]
Hi there, my name is Mike and here's how
to chat with Copilot in Business
Central. Copilot is your AI companion
for work and you'll find it providing
assistance across all kinds of features
in Business Central, but from anywhere
and at any time. You can chat with
C-pilot in Business Central as well.
I'll show you how this works. Think of
this as an easy way to uh really
interact with your business data using
natural language so that you can find
records um by filtering, sorting and
searching on that data. But it's also a
way to uh learn new skills with Business
Central. So whether you're uh new to
Business Central and just learning how
things work or you're trying to master
those uh you know little tricks that
really raise your game when it comes to
working with your data. Let's dive in
now and let's check out a few examples.
All right, so to chat with Copilot,
simply find the Copilot icon in the app
bar and that brings up the copilot pane.
And let's start with a really important
question for my business. Which customer
owes me most
money? So here I've put co-pilot to work
on its very first task, which is
figuring out which of my customers uh
owes me the most, which has the most uh
amount due. And um here it's going to
come back and present this information
to me in a way that I can work with. Uh
give me a record presented as a neat and
compact tile. Shows all of the essential
information about that customer. And
it's a school of fine art. Uh and they
have a balance of $53,000. Now that's
definitely worth diving into a little
bit more. So, let's double click into
that and see um does our customer ledger
show any payments from them this
week. So, before I contact this customer
about their balance, um I want to make
sure that they haven't registered any
payments. Now, there's an important
point here to understand which is
copilot doesn't have access to my
company bank accounts. It only knows
about the data within business central
in this case. So here it's looking at my
customer ledger entries, looking at
other information to figure out do we
have a payment that's been registered in
Business Central. Also really important
to understand when I put Copilot to work
to find things for me, Copilot has
access to only the records that I
already have access to. It's working on
my behalf. Doesn't access anything else.
So here it's come back and said there
are zero results. There are zero
payments that have been registered. Hm.
Interesting. So, um, maybe the next
thing I want to do is check what's the
easiest way to remind customers to pay
up. Smiley. Well, now this is a very
different style of question, isn't it?
Now, I'm not asking C-Pilot to find
records. Uh, I'm actually asking for
assistance to learn how to use Business
Central better and has come up with this
recommendation of using the reminders
feature and how to get to it and how to
get started. Um, okay, fantastic. So
that's one little conversation. Let's
try something else. Uh so imagine, you
know, a customer calls in um has a quote
and wants to upgrade that to an order.
Fantastic. So I could type find quote
and put in the the quote number, the the
number of that document. Um but many
times, you know, when you get that
email, when you get that customer call,
the number is not your starting point.
So you want to start with the name of
the customer. So let's try that. Find
the latest quote for Relic Cloud.
Now, notice how loosely I've described
what I'm looking for here. I said quote.
I wasn't specific that this is a sales
quote. Uh, Copilot could have gone and
figured out, you know, gone and looked
at my assembly quotes or my purchase
quotes. Uh, but Copilot knows me best.
It knows what are my favorite pages, for
example, based on the bookmarks that I
have on my roll center. So, it's figured
out that sales quotes is probably what
I'm after in this case. And sure enough,
it's come back and found the sales quote
103. is presented that information into
this compact tile with all the essential
fields as
well. Now before I proceed with this
customer, I want to make sure I
understand uh the state of this quote.
So let's see when does this quote
expire. So I can now ask Copilot for
specific fields on these records as
well. And um also note that there's no
field called expire or expiry. So,
Copilot will try to match what I'm
asking for in the language that I choose
uh with the fields that actually exist
on that record. And the field in this
case is actually called quote valid
until date. Uh and it's come back and
given me that answer right here. July
16, 25. Excellent. Now, that got me
thinking, what if there are more quotes
expiring this week? Let's check with
Copilot again. Any quotes expiring this
week? Now, same thing here. Copilot is
often looking through my records. It's
going to come back with a response and
present that to me. And because I'm
talking about a specific field uh which
isn't normally part of the you know
handful of fields we show on the tile
for a record uh here it's actually going
to add that to my tiles so I can even
easily compare. So this one is valid
until 606. This one's 605. Uh so that
information is all available there. Now
um all throughout this conversation
you've probably realized a couple of
things. One of them is you'll see
citation controls like this. You'll see
a a reference uh list like this. And
these are essentially ways for me to
understand where did Copilot source this
information from? Uh was it from the
Business Central database? Uh if we're
looking up information, did that come
from Microsoft online documentation? And
this is a great way for me to understand
that Copilot has figured it out the
right way. It has applied the right
filters and sorting to come up with an
answer. If you check out this one, look
how it's converted my natural language
question into a way to filter the sales
quotes with those expiring with the
range between June 2nd and June 8th. So,
u this helps you just really quickly
double check that Copilot has used the
right logic to come up with the answer.
All right. Now, if you can't see the
C-pilot pane or you don't seem to be
able to get it working, there's a few
things admins can do to make sure that
this is all set up correctly. So the
first thing is admins can go to the
co-pilot and agent capabilities page.
This is the page that lists all of the
copilot and agent functionality that is
available in your environment very
specifically. Look for the line that
says chat. Uh make sure it's active. If
it's not, there's an action that you can
use to activate that. So that's the
first thing you need to make sure is set
correctly. Secondly, let's look at
permissions.
If I go to permission sets, you'll find
that there's a new permission set for
Copilot. And this contains all the
C-pilot system features um including
chat. So, make sure that your users have
this assigned if they're not able to
access uh chat. This is probably what's
missing. This is a permission that was
introduced with update 26. Uh all users
should have it by default, but admins
can of course configure that. Okay, so
uh bit of a change of gears now. Let's
have a completely different conversation
with Copilot. Now, this conversation has
already gotten pretty long. And just
like if you and I were having that chat
together, sometimes you lose sight of
what the context is and things get a bit
difficult. And it's the same for
Copilot. So, help Copilot out by
occasionally clearing the chat using
this button right here. That will
essentially reset the chat and allow you
to start a new conversation, a new
thread with Copilot. It increases the
chances of of success.
So now for our next conversation,
managing inventory is of course an
essential part of our business. So I'm
going to ask some inventory management
questions to co-pilot here. Let's start
with this one. Do we have any chairs in
stock for under
$200? So here I've put Copilot to work
with looking through my inventory. Uh
notice how I didn't point specifically
to the items list. I didn't need to
mention that. Copilot will figure out
that I'm talking about uh my products
that I sell. Um now this was also one of
the uh first use cases we added to um to
Business Central to Copilot. Uh and
since then it we've improved it greatly.
Uh it's faster, it's more performance,
it's more reliable. Uh and you can see
how it comes back with a couple of uh
products here displayed beautifully as
tiles including that item picture um
where I can get that information. So
here these are also interactive. I'm
going to click and drill into the Berlin
guest chair. It opens up the record
right alongside chat so I can continue
working. Let's check my inventory here.
The quantity looks correct. I've got my
stockout warnings. Um, and under
planning, I see I'm not taking advantage
of the reordering policy in Business
Central, and I'm not really sure how
that works. So, from the tool tip, I can
actually ask Copilot to help me
understand what reordering policy is and
how that works. So now it's again
searching Microsoft's online
documentation to come up with an answer.
Um, and here it's found plenty of
information. Again, I've got those
citations where I can go and read up in
more detail about how to use reorder
policy and apply that to my business
central. Now I'm more interested in
what's not in stock or what's very low
stock at this point in time. So let me
ask a different style of question. Let's
show low stock
inventory by
category. All right. So now Copilot
recognizes that some kind of questions
are best answered by displaying
structured information and the best tool
for the job is of course analysis tabs.
So here it's presenting me with a very
simple option so that with one click
copilot will open the items list. it
will use my words to generate an an
analysis tab for me. Uh it'll present
that information on screen uh for me to
get an answer to my question, get me
closer to an answer. So here you can see
I've got my desks, I got my chairs.
We'll take a look through
that. And I'd like to add some
additional essential information. So
let's go and add the um let's see add
vendor and substitutes.
So now I'm asking Copilot to modify this
analysis view uh and include some
additional columns that may be useful
for me to understand situation with my
inventory. I've got my quantity there.
I've got my vendors and I've got my list
of substitutes. And I've just noticed
that the London swivel chair has no
substitute products defined. And that's
obviously a risk because I want my
sellers to be able to continue selling
alternatives when uh stock is low. All
right. So now I'm on the item
substitution page and it's blank. What
do I do? How do I use this? Um, luckily
Copilot can help me out here too. So hey
Copilot, what can you help me with on
the current page? So Copilot is now
aware of other capabilities it has that
are very contextual to the currently
open page in Business Central. And here
one of the things Copilot can help with
is to actually suggest these values. It
can also help me analyze the list, but
the list is empty right now. So I want
to suggest item substitutes. With a
single click, it's activated that
capability. And this actually works with
any custom capabilities you've added
also um through the extensions that you
have installed as well. Copilot will
recognize them from chat and suggest
them inside the copilot pane. So let's
keep a couple of these. I'm just going
to remove a couple of these uh chairs
that we have here. Uh we'll just keep
the swivel chairs. I'll insert those.
And I'm actually done with my task. So,
um those are a couple of example
conversations you can have with Copilot.
Um if you want to try it out and get
hands-on, if you're looking for
inspiration, what you can do is you can
use the prompt guide right here. This is
packed with all kinds of useful example
prompts that you can use to find records
or to explain concepts. For example, how
do I do some task? And these are just
like templates in a way. As I choose it,
it's inserted the text that I can then
finish off and send to copilot. So, how
do I resize the side
pane? And copilot here will search again
our online documentation. Uh, but it's
also now aware of local functionality
documentation. It's aware of release
plans as well about upcoming features or
features that are new in this release.
And here it's found about one fantastic
new feature that helps you adjust the
factbox uh uh pane with in business
central as well. So what would you ask
copilot? Uh give it a try on your
business central and let us know how it
goes. Give us some feedback. We really
appreciate that. So if you'd like to see
more videos like this, just like and
subscribe. You'll get plenty more like
this. Uh we hope you found this
informative and useful and wish you a
productive day chatting with Copilot.